http://www.essentialsupplies.co.uk/privacy-policy

ShopPowerPower Distribution UnitsBespoke Power Distribution16A Power Distribution32A Power Distribution63 Power Distribution125A Power Distribution400A Power DistributionCable ProtectionComponentsEnclosuresTripsInspection WindowsPlugs & SocketsSingle Phase 230v16A Plugs & Sockets16A Inlets & Outlets32A Plugs & Sockets32A Inlets & Outlets63A Plugs & Sockets63A Inlets & Outlets125A Plugs & Sockets125A Inlets & OutletsMennekes PlugsThree Phase 400v16A Plugs & Sockets16A Inlets & Outlets32A Plugs & Sockets32A Inlets & Outlets63A Plugs & Sockets63A Inlets & Outlets125A Plugs & Sockets125A Inlets & Outlets13A, 10A & IEC13A Plugs & Sockets10A Plugs & Sockets10A IEC16A IEC15A & PowerCONEuropean RangeLow Voltage110 VoltMarine & ReeferInterlocked SocketsMennekes PlugsCablesExtension Leads16A32A63A125A150A -400A PowerlockPowerCONIEC13AMarine and Reefer CablesExtension ReelsLoose CableSocapexCable AccessoriesCable Storage Carrier BoxHeat ShrinkCable GlandsCable CrossingsCable JoinersAdaptorsIEC AdaptorsPowerCON Adaptors13A Adaptors16A Adaptors32A Adaptors63A AdaptorsCustom AdaptorsTransformersTesters13A Test PlugsMultimeterVoltage DetectorPAT Testers3 Phase Test Plugs110v Construction110v Plugs & Sockets110v Cables110v AdaptorsSite LightingLightingUtility & WarehouseStrip LightsHigh Bay Flood LightsEmergency LightsLow Bay Flood LightsLow Energy LightsExteriorExhibition LightingMarquee Hotel & VenueVintage HangingChandeliers & PendantsPaper LanternsLight Fittings for Paper LanternsProfiles & FresnelsVintage LightingLED TapesStrip LightsFestoon & Fairy LightsFestoon LightingTraditional SeriesConnectable SeriesLightweight SeriesColoured FestoonCustom Made FestoonWhite FestoonBattery SeriesFairy LightsPars & Stage LightsLED ParsPin SpotsBatten LED BarsTraditional PAR CansFresnels and ProfilesBirdie Cans Par 16UplightersMoving LightsDisco & EffectsDisco LightsMirrorballLasersFilter GelsHaze, Smoke, Snow & BubblesControlDimmersLighting DesksWireless DMXDMX SplittersDMX Control CablesSpare LampsDecorative LampsGolf Ball LampsCandle BulbsStandard GLSStage LampsGU LampsHQI LampsPAR Lamps & SpotlampsAudioMicrophonesMixing ConsolesAnalogue MixersDigital MixersSpeakersFBT AudioDB TechnologiesBattery Powered SpeakersStandsCableCable TestersSignal CableJackXLRStageboxAccessoriesMedia PlayersDIsDriveRackCasesRiggingWires & RopesWire RopeSafety Wires & SteelsGripple & Wire FixingsShackles & HooksRopesPulleysChainBungee CordsStands & ClampsCouplers & ClampsStandsTruss SystemsDURATRUSSLadderSmall 22 SeriesStandard 32 SeriesTriangularStandard 33/2 SeriesSmall 23 SeriesQuadStandard 34/2 SeriesSmall 24/2 SeriesMicro 14 SeriesOpti TriliteMetalworxExhibition TrussTruss CoversTruss RiggingChain BlocksShacklesLifting StropsSafety & Rigging WiresRigging SteelsRatchets & StrapsFastenersMasonry BoltsEye Nuts & BoltsWing NutsThumb ScrewsNailsClips & PinsPortable StagingLecternsEventsMarquee RiggingMarquee Wires & RopesMarquee ClampsMarquee Ratchet StrapsQuick Fix SystemFastenersMarquee ToolsLaddersTape MeasuresHand ToolsHealth & SafetyStake PullersSledge HammersMarquee FansMarquee StagingOutdoor HeatingPub Bar Beer GardenElectrical PowerFestoon String LightingOutdoor LightingParty at homeAccessoriesToolsHand ToolsTape MeasuresLaddersCable TiesStandardReleasableStainless SteelAdhesive TapesGaffer TapeWide Gaffer TapeCarpet TapeCable Protection TapeInsulation TapeSafety TapeVelcroBatteriesHealth & SafetyStorageBespoke Flight CasesSpecial OffersEBAY SalesESSENTIAL RANGELighting OffersPower OffersRigging OffersMiscellaneous Offers Ex-DemoEV ChargingSpecial ProjectsBespoke ServicesTemporary StructuresPower SolutionsLighting SolutionsTesting & RepairPubs, Bars & Beer GardensTraining CoursesEvent ElectricalEvent LightingPAT Testing For EventsCase StudiesManchester Kampus MenuContactHelpDelivery & ReturnsAbout UsMy AccountBlog Home Privacy Policy
Privacy PolicyEssential Supplies Limited are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.This policy [together with our terms of use [https://www.essentialsupplies.co.uk/terms-conditions] and any other documents referred to on it] sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us.Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it. By visiting https://www.essentialsupplies.co.uk you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this policy.We collect certain information or data about you when you use https://www.essentialsupplies.co.uk We collect:: Questions, queries or feedback you leave, including your email address if you visit https://www.essentialsupplies.co.uk: Your email address and subscription preferences when you sign up to our email alerts, and how you use our emails – for example whether you open them and which links you click on: Your IP address, and details of which version of web browser you used: Information on how you use the site, using cookies and page tagging techniquesThis data can be viewed by authorised people within Essential Supplies Limited to:: Improve the site by monitoring how you use it: Gather feedback to improve our services, for example our email alerts: Respond to any feedback you send us, if you’ve asked us to: Send email alerts to users who request them: Allow you to access government services and make transactions: Provide you with information about local services if you want it FOR WHAT PURPOSES DO WE PROCESS YOUR DATA:E-Mail NewsletterWe use a third party provider, Sender (https://www.sender.net), to deliver our monthly e-newsletters. We gather statistics around email opening and clicks using industry standard technologies including clear gifs to help us monitor and improve our e-newsletter. For more information, please see Sender’s privacy policy by visiting https://www.sender.net/privacy-policy
Security and performanceEssential Supplies use a third party service to help maintain the security and performance of the Essential Supplies website. To deliver this service it processes the IP addresses of visitors to the ICO website.WordPressWe use a third party service, WordPress.org, to publish our blog. This website is hosted by Teclan (https://www.teclan.com) our website host. We use a standard WordPress service to collect anonymous information about users' activity on the site, for example the number of users viewing pages on the site, to monitor and report on the effectiveness of the site and help us improve it. WordPress requires visitors that want to post a comment to enter a name and email address. For more information about how WordPress processes data, please WordPress at https://wordpress.org/about/privacyWHERE YOUR DATA IS STOREDWe store your data on secure servers in the European Economic Area (EEA) (except for data that we gather when you sign up to our email alerts).By submitting your personal data, you agree to this.HOW LONG DO WE RETAIN YOUR DATAWe keep your data until a request has been received to have your data removed.WHEN YOU SIGN UP TO OUR EMAIL ALERTSWe use the Sender Delivery platform, for our email alerts.As a subscriber to our email newsletter, we may contact you from time to time to inform you of company updates or interesting marketing information, we will also provide clear opt out instructions at the base of all marketing email communications should you wish not to receive communication from us in future.As a data processor on behalf of Essential Supplies Limited, (Sender) will use your information to send you email alerts if you request them. You can find out more about how Sender collects and stores your information here https://www.sender.net/privacy-policy
KEEPING YOUR DATA SECURESending information over the internet is generally not completely secure, and we can’t guarantee the security of your data while it’s in transit. Any data you send is at your own risk.We have robust procedures and security features compliant with the GDPR in place to keep your data secure once we receive it.DISCLOSING YOUR INFORMATIONWe may pass on your personal information if we have a legal obligation to do so, or if we must enforce or apply our terms of use and other agreements. This includes exchanging information with other government departments for legal reasons.We won’t share your information with any other organisations for marketing, market research or commercial purposes, and we don’t pass on your details to other websites.YOUR RIGHTSYou can find out what information we hold about you and ask us not to use any of the information we collect.If you’ve signed up for email alerts, you can unsubscribe or change your settings at any time.To discuss our privacy policy or your individual rights you can contact Louise Chugg, Commercial Manager by email, louise@essentialsupplies.co.ukLINKS TO OTHER WEBSITEShttps://www.essentialsupplies.co.uk contains links to other websites.This privacy policy only applies to https://www.essentialsupplies.co.uk, and doesn’t cover other services that we link to. These services have their own terms and conditions and privacy policies.Following a link to another website:If you go to another website from this one, read the privacy policy on that website to find out what it does with your information.Following a link to https://www.essentialsupplies.co.uk from another website:If you come to https://www.essentialsupplies.co.uk from another website, we may receive information from the other website. We don’t use this data. You should read the privacy policy of the website you came from to find out more about this. CONCERNS OR COMPLAINTS If you have any complaints in relation to how our business has processed your data or in relation to the exercise of your rights as detailed above you can in the first instance raise your concerns by contacting us as follows: Louise Chugg, Commercial Manager, louise@essentialsupplies.co.uk You may also contact the Information Commissioner’s Office in relation to any such complaints https://ico.org.ukCOOKIES POLICYWe use cookies on our website to provide you with the best possible user experience. We do this by placing a small text file or cookie on your device/computer hard drive to track how you use our website to record or log whether you have seen particular messages that we display, to keep you logged into the website where applicable.Some cookies are required to use the full functionality of our website.Your web browser should provide you with the controls to manage and delete cookies from your device, please see your web browser options.We use Google Analytics to monitor website visitors. Google Analytics sets first party cookies via a piece of JavaScript code which must be added to every page that site owners want to track. It sets four cookies automatically, and a fifth via opt-in (this relates to sharing information about your traffic with Google).For further information regarding Google Analytics cookies visit:https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookie-usage
